Joseph E. Persico Papers MS126
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Joseph E. Persico Papers
1950 -- 1985
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Persico, Joseph E.
MS126
2.33 Linear Feet 3 oversize boxes
1 Audiovisual Object(s)
3 Digital Object(s)
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series.
Custodial History
The materials housed in this collection were donated by Mr. Persico on May 25, 1991 via a letter from him to Mr. Hewson Ryan of the Edward R. Murrow Center. While Mr. Perisco placed no restrictions on the use or publication of these materials, the audio cassettes in this collection may be subject to privacy concerns.
No accession number exists. The collection arrived in 1991 and went first to the Fletcher School (Murrow Center) and then came later to the DCA. The university was without an archivist from 1991-1997.Due to this gap, we believe the collection was never formerly accessioned.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes audio tapes, correspondence, reports, notes, clippings, and ancillary materials used by Joseph E. Persico in writing the biography, Edward R. Murrow: An American Original. The bulk of the material dates from 1984 to 1985 and pertains to the interviews conducted for the book. Significant interviewees include the family of Edward Murrow, Walter Cronkite, Fred Friendly, and Lauren Bacall. Subject files pertain to the book and to the interviewees and include correspondence between Joe Persico and those interviewed, notes, and clippings regarding those interviewed. Also included are Freedom of Information files on Edward Murrow requested by Persico. Materials are arranged alphabetically.
Joseph Persico's papers are held at the University of New York, Albany and Stanford University's Hoover Institution Library and Archives.
Biographical / Historical
Joseph E. Persico was born July 19, 1930 in Gloversville, New York. In 1952, after receiving a BA in both English and Political Science from the New York State College for Teachers, he entered the U.S. Navy and remained in the military for three years. In 1956, Persico enrolled at Columbia University to begin his graduate work. His career as a political writer began that same year. In 1966, he became the chief speechwriter for New York Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller, remaining Rockefeller's primary speechwriter as the Governor served as Vice President of the United States from 1974 to 1977. Afterward, Persico became a full-time author, focusing on historical subjects. In 1990, he wrote a biography of Edward R. Murrow entitled Edward R. Murrow: An American Original.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to this collection is restricted. Some materials are closed for 75 years due to privacy concerns.
Joseph E. Persico; Edward. R. Murrow; Interviews--United States; Media and broadcast history
- Audiocassettes, 1961 -- 1985; MS126.001; 0.6 Linear Feet; 1 Audiovisual Object(s); 3 Digital Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  The bulk of these audiocassettes consist of Joe Persico's interviews with Murrow's family, friends and colleagues.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically by interviewee.
  Conditions Governing Access
  75 years from the date of creation.
  - Aaron, Betsy, 1985-01-07; MS126.001.001.00001 (Case 1)
    audiocassette
  - Anderson, Burnett, 1985-01-07; MS126.001.001.00002 (Case 1)
  - Bacall, Lauren, 1985-03-19; MS126.001.001.00003 (Case 1)
  - Bliss, Ed - Newburyport, 1984-07-13; MS126.001.001.00004 (Case 1)
  - Bliss, Ed - Newburyport, 1984-07-13; MS126.001.001.00005 (Case 1)
  - Brinkley, David, 1985-03-06; MS126.001.001.00006 (Case 1)
  - Bundy, McGeorge, 1984-10-05; MS126.001.001.00007 (Case 1)
  - Clark, Blair, 1984-09-20; MS126.001.001.00008 (Case 1)
  - Clark, Blair, 1984-09-20; MS126.001.001.00009 (Case 1)
  - Clodius, Katherine - La Jolla, 1985-02-05; MS126.001.001.00010 (Case 1)
  - Coie, Paul, 1985-02-13; MS126.001.001.00011 (Case 1)
  - Colin, Ralph, 1984-06-05; MS126.001.001.00012 (Case 1)
  - Collingwood, Charles - NYC, 1984-09-06; MS126.001.001.00013 (Case 1)
  - Collingwood, Charles - NYC, 1984-09-21; MS126.001.001.00014 (Case 1)
  - Collingwood, Charles - NYC, 1984-09-21; MS126.001.001.00015 (Case 1)
  - Collingwood, Charles - NYC, 1984-10-02; MS126.001.001.00016 (Case 1)
  - Collingwood, Charles - NYC, 1985-01-10; MS126.001.001.00017 (Case 1)
  - Corwin, Norman, 1985-02-06; MS126.001.001.00018 (Case 1)
  - Cox, Dorothy Baas - AARP, 1984-08-07; MS126.001.001.00019 (Case 1)
  - Cronkite, Walter - Telcon, 1984-11-26; MS126.001.001.00020 (Case 1)
  - Daley, John Charles, 1985-03-25; MS126.001.001.00021 (Case 1)
  - Daley, John Charles, 1985-03-25; MS126.001.001.00022 (Case 1)
  - Decker, Hermine Duthie - Telcon, 1985-05-19; MS126.001.001.00023 (Case 1)
  - DePoris, Gene - Telcon, 1985-01-28; MS126.001.001.00024 (Case 1)
  - Diamond, Vernon - Telcon, 1985-01-28; MS126.001.001.00025 (Case 1)
  - Dixon, Bob, 1984-06-27; MS126.001.001.00026 (Case 1)
  - Dixon, Bob, 1984-06-27; MS126.001.001.00027 (Case 1)
  - Downs, Rosaline, 1984-10-04; MS126.001.001.00028 (Case 1)
  - Edwards, Douglas - NYC, 1984-09-07; MS126.001.001.00029 (Case 1)
  - Eismann, Bernard - Telcon, 1985-01-29; MS126.001.001.00030 (Case 1)
  - Evans, Robert - Telcon, 1985-02-28; MS126.001.001.00031 (Case 1)
  - Evans, Robert - Telcon, 1985-02-28; MS126.001.001.00032 (Case 1)
  - Foster, Robert, 1985-02-05; MS126.001.001.00033 (Case 1)
  - Friel, Jack; Delysch, Mrs. Classmate of Ida Lou., 1985-02-15; MS126.001.001.00034 (Case 1)
  - Friendly, Fred, 1984-03-27; MS126.001.001.00035 (Case 1)
  - Friendly, Fred, 1984-07-11; MS126.001.001.00036 (Case 1)
  - Friendly, Fred, 1984-12-20; MS126.001.001.00037 (Case 1)
  - Galbraith, Catherine and John Kenneth - Telcon, 1984-01-03; MS126.001.001.00038 (Case 1)
  - Garvaist, Frank; Gibbs, Georgia; Gerundi II, 1984-06-05; MS126.001.001.00039 (Case 1)
  - Goldwyn, Sam Jr., 1985-02-07; MS126.001.001.00040 (Case 1)
  - Goldwyn, Sam Jr., 1985-02-07; MS126.001.001.00041 (Case 1)
  - Hetzel, Ralph, 1985-02-06; MS126.001.001.00042 (Case 1)
  - Hewitt, Don, 1984-09-05; MS126.001.002.00001 (Case 2)
  - Hill, Willma Dudley, 1985-04-22; MS126.001.002.00002 (Case 2)
  - Hill, Willma Dudley, 1985-04-22; MS126.001.002.00003 (Case 2)
  - Hirschon, 1985-01-24; MS126.001.002.00004 (Case 2)
  - Hottelot, Richard C. & Hottelot, Mrs., 1984-09-07 -- 1984-09-26; MS126.001.002.00005 (Case 2)
  - Gruelich, Nancy, 1985-02-08; MS126.001.002.00006 (Case 2)
  - Kalb, Marvin - Washington, DC, 1985-05-16; MS126.001.002.00007 (Case 2)
  - Katterle, Mrs. Zeno (Key), nee Fulton, 1985-02-27; MS126.001.002.00008 (Case 2)
  - Kendrick, Alexander, 1985-03-22; MS126.001.002.00009 (Case 2)
  - Kirkpatrick, Rear Admiral Charles C., 1985-03-16; MS126.001.002.00010 (Case 2)
  - Kreager, Dr. Dewayne, 1985-02-13; MS126.001.002.00011 (Case 2)
  - Leonard, Bill - D.C., 1984-09-18; MS126.001.002.00012 (Case 2)
  - Lincoln, Evelyn - D.C., 1985-06-03; MS126.001.002.00013 (Case 2)
  - Loomis, Henry, 1984-10-19; MS126.001.002.00014 (Case 2)
  - Loomis, Henry, 1984-10-19; MS126.001.002.00015 (Case 2)
  - McKnight, John, 1985-01-10; MS126.001.002.00016 (Case 2)
  - Mickelson, Sig, 1985-02-04; MS126.001.002.00017 (Case 2)
  - Mickelson, Sig, 1985-02-04; MS126.001.002.00018 (Case 2)
  - Morgan, Edward, 1985-02-25; MS126.001.002.00019 (Case 2)
  - Murrow, Casey - Brattleboro, VT, 1985-09-05; MS126.001.002.00020 (Case 2)
  - Murrow, Casey - Brattleboro, VT, 1985-09-05; MS126.001.002.00021 (Case 2)
  - Murrow, Casey - Brattleboro, VT, 1985-09-05; MS126.001.002.00022 (Case 2)
  - Murrow, Nell; Murrow, John - Polecat Creek, NC, 1985-05-04; MS126.001.002.00023 (Case 2)
  - Murrow, Janet - 116 E. 66, NYC, 1984-06-26; MS126.001.002.00024 (Case 2)
  - Murrow, Janet - 116 E. 66, NYC, 1984-06-27; MS126.001.002.00025 (Case 2)
  - Murrow, Janet, 1984-07-26; MS126.001.002.00026 (Case 2)
  - Murrow, Janet, MS126.001.002.00027 (Case 2)
    No Date available
  - Murrow, Janet, MS126.001.002.00028 (Case 2)
    No date available
  - Murrow, Janet, MS126.001.002.00029 (Case 2)
  - Murrow, Janet, MS126.001.002.00030 (Case 2)
  - Murrow, Janet, 1984-09-11 -- 1984-09-15; MS126.001.002.00031 (Case 2)
  - Murrow, Janet, 1984-09-11 -- 1984-09-15; MS126.001.002.00032 (Case 2)
  - Murrow, Janet (9/11/84 - 9/15/84), 1984; MS126.001.002.00033 (Case 2)
    2 sides, 45 min/side.
  - Murrow, Janet, 1984-12-07; MS126.001.002.00034 (Case 2)
  - Murrow, Janet, 1984-12-07; MS126.001.002.00035 (Case 2)
  - Murrow, Maggie, 1985-02-10; MS126.001.002.00036 (Case 2)
  - Murrow, Maggie, 1985-02-10; MS126.001.002.00037 (Case 2)
  - Nelson, Josh, 1985-02-04; MS126.001.002.00038 (Case 2)
  - Paley, Bill - Transcribed, 1984-06-01; MS126.001.002.00039 (Case 2)
  - Paley, Bill - Transcribed, 1984-11-26; MS126.001.002.00040 (Case 2)
  - Pierpoint, Cort, 1985-02-26; MS126.001.002.00041 (Case 2)
  - Pierpoint, Cort, 1985-02-26; MS126.001.002.00042 (Case 2)
  - Pierpoint, Cort, 1985-02-26; MS126.001.003.00001 (Case 3)
  - Plesent, Stanley - Telcon, 1985-05-28; MS126.001.003.00002 (Case 3)
  - Powell, Justice Lewis (Failed to record), 1984-09-17; MS126.001.003.00003 (Case 3)
  - Ream, Joseph, 1984-10-11; MS126.001.003.00004 (Case 3)
  - Reasoner, Harry, 1985-01-17; MS126.001.003.00005 (Case 3)
  - Reston, Scotty, 1984-12-04; MS126.001.003.00006 (Case 3)
  - Rowan, Carl, 1985-07-12; MS126.001.003.00007 (Case 3)
  - Rubin, Mrs. Charlotte, 1985-02-28; MS126.001.003.00008 (Case 3)
  - Ryan, Hewson - Murrow Center, 1984-07-12; MS126.001.003.00009 (Case 3)
  - Raymond, Helen [Hazen?] - college friend, 1985-02-14; MS126.001.003.00010 (Case 3)
  - Salant, Richard, 1984-10-26; MS126.001.003.00011 (Case 3)
  - Salk, Dr. Jonas, 1981-02-04; MS126.001.003.00012 (Case 3)
    - Salk, Dr. Jonas, 1981-02-04; MS126.001.003.00012.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 234 Megabytes
      Side 1
    - Salk, Dr. Jonas, 1981-02-04; MS126.001.003.00012.00002; 1 Digital Object(s); 233 Megabytes
      Side 2
  - Salk, Dr. Jonas; Music, side 4, 1981-02-04; MS126.001.003.00013 (Case 3)
    - Salk, Dr. Jonas; Music, side 4, 1981-02-04; MS126.001.003.00013.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 54.5 Megabytes
  - Sandberg, Robert - Telcon, 1985-02-12; MS126.001.003.00014 (Case 3)
  - Schaeffer, Franklin - Telcon, 1985-02-07; MS126.001.003.00015 (Case 3)
  - Schmidt, Lewis, 1985-06-04; MS126.001.003.00016 (Case 3)
  - Schoenbrun, David - NYC, 1985-01-24; MS126.001.003.00017 (Case 3)
  - Schorr, Dan - Telcon, 1984-10-17; MS126.001.003.00018 (Case 3)
  - Sevareid, Eric, 1984-10-10; MS126.001.003.00019 (Case 3)
  - Sevareid, Eric, 1984-10-10; MS126.001.003.00020 (Case 3)
  - Sevareid, Eric, 1984-10-10; MS126.001.003.00021 (Case 3)
  - Seward, James Morgan - Hanover, NH, 1984-07-14; MS126.001.003.00022 (Case 3)
  - Seward, James Morgan - Hanover, NH, 1984-07-14; MS126.001.003.00023 (Case 3)
  - Scheftel, Stuart - NYC, 1984-11-29; MS126.001.003.00024 (Case 3)
  - Shirer, Teresa, 1984-10-05; MS126.001.003.00025 (Case 3)
  - Shirer, William L., 1984-08-20; MS126.001.003.00026 (Case 3)
  - Shirer, William L., 1984-08-20; MS126.001.003.00027 (Case 3)
  - Sioussat, Helen, 1984-06-12; MS126.001.003.00028 (Case 3)
  - Sioussat, Helen - Italy, 1984-08-07; MS126.001.003.00029 (Case 3)
  - Smith, Howard K., 1984-08-31; MS126.001.003.00030 (Case 3)
  - Sorenson, Tom - Darien, Conn., 1984-07-09; MS126.001.003.00031 (Case 3)
  - Sorenson, Tom - Darien, Conn., 1984-07-09; MS126.001.003.00032 (Case 3)
  - Stanton, Frank - NYC, 1984-06-25; MS126.001.003.00033 (Case 3)
  - Stanton, Frank - NYC, 1984-06-29; MS126.001.003.00034 (Case 3)
  - Tree, Marietta - NYC, 1984-10-11; MS126.001.003.00035 (Case 3)
  - Trout, Robert, 1985-01-18; MS126.001.003.00036 (Case 3)
  - Warburg, 1985-04-30; MS126.001.003.00037 (Case 3)
  - Wershba, Joseph - NYC, 1984-09-05; MS126.001.003.00038 (Case 3)
  - White, Teddy, 1984-11-28; MS126.001.003.00039 (Case 3)
  - Williams, Chester, 1984-08-21; MS126.001.003.00040 (Case 3)
  - Williams, Chester, 1984-08-21; MS126.001.003.00041 (Case 3)
  - Williams, Palmer, 1984-11-29; MS126.001.003.00042 (Case 3)
  - Williams, Palmer, 1984-11-29; MS126.001.004.00001 (Case 4)
  - Wilson, Don, 1984-06-25; MS126.001.004.00002 (Case 4)
  - Wilson, Don, 1984-06-25; MS126.001.004.00003 (Case 4)
  - Zousmer, Steven, 1985-01-16; MS126.001.004.00004 (Case 4)
  - Beck, Jack, 1985-02-08; MS126.001.004.00005 (Case 4)
  - Farewell to Studio 9, Produced by CBS News, 1964-07-25; MS126.001.004.00006 (Case 4)
  - M Farewell, 1961-01-31; MS126.001.004.00007 (Case 4)
  - Cioffi, Lou - Telcon, 1985-02-26; MS126.001.004.00008 (Case 4)
  - McClendon, Sara - Telcon, 1984-08-31; MS126.001.004.00009 (Case 4)
  - Pavlovsky, Santiago [Pano?], 1984-09-10; MS126.001.004.00010 (Case 4)
  - Patterson, Mary Marvin, 1984-10-09; MS126.001.004.00011 (Case 4)
  - HBO "Murrow", MS126.001.004.00012 (Case 4)
  - Wiesner, Jerome - Boston, Telcon, 1985-05-07; MS126.001.004.00013 (Case 4)
  - Wilson, Eleanor D. - NYC, 1984-10-25; MS126.001.004.00014 (Case 4)
  - Murrow, Donnie, 1985-02-13 -- 1985-02-14; MS126.001.004.00015 (Case 4)
  - Murrow, Donnie, 1985-02-13 -- 1985-02-14; MS126.001.004.00016 (Case 4)
  - Sanders, Les, MS126.001.004.00017 (Case 4)
  - Sanders, Les, 1985-03-08; MS126.001.004.00018 (Case 4)
- Additional accessions, 1950 -- 1985; MS126.002; 1 Volumes
  Open for research.
  - Edward Murrow Bibliography Files, Box 1, 1950 -- 1985; MS025-001 (Box 1)
    Unknown accession number; donation by Joe Persico: Persico's correspondence files re book including photographs and FOI files of Murrow, green barcoded on May 4, 2007. Previously stored with other unknown accessions in stacks. former barcode 39090014011114g
  - Edward Murrow Bibliography Files, Box 2, 1950 -- 1985; MS025-002 (Box 2)
    Unknown accession number; donation by Joe Persico: Persico's correspondence files re book including photographs and FOI files of Murrow,, green barcoded on May 4, 2007. Previously stored with other unknown accessions in stacks. former barcode 39090014011122g